Annus A. Siddiqui, RN, BSN

18w237 Knollwood Lane Villa Park, IL 60181 (630) 525-0908 Sid@SidSiddiqui.com

OBJECTIVE

Bachelor of Science in Nursing holder from Purdue University and current MBA candidate with a strong academic and clinical background in nursing combined with over five years of supervisory and medical experience in health care, ranging from both acute to sub-acute clinical environments. BLS, ACLS, and NIHSS certified, as well as proficient in a variety of nursing specialties, with specific regards to supervisory roles. Regarded as a focused and avid learner with a responsible work ethic, which would be well suited for a variety of professional and educational opportunities.

LICENSURE & CERTIFICATIONS

Illinois State RN License: August 2014 - May 2018

Illinois State LPN License (Inactive): January 2012 - January 31, 2015

ACLS - Advanced Cardiovascular Life Support: November 2016

BLS - Basic Life Support for Healthcare Providers: November 2016

NIH Stroke Scale Training and Certification: November 2014

EDUCATION

Graduate Degree

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign

Degree: Masters of Business Administration (MBA) - In Progress, expected 2019

<u>Undergraduate Degrees</u>

Purdue University

Degree: Bachelor of Science in Nursing - December 2016

Honors: Deans List, Academic Honors

Graduating GPA: 3.84

College of DuPage

Degree: Associate in Science - May 2015

Associate in Applied Science of Nursing - May 2014

Associate in Arts - December 2012

Honors: Academic Honors

WORK EXPERIENCE

Fresenius Medical Care NA, Elmhurst, IL

RN Team Leader/Inpatient Services RN, September 2015 - Current

Lakewood Nursing and Rehabilitation Center, Plainfield, IL

Nursing Supervisor/Staff Nurse, February 2015 - October 2015

Courtyard Healthcare Center, Berwyn, IL

Nursing Supervisor, February 2012 - January 2015

CLINICAL RESPONSIBILITIES

Fresenius Medical Care NA

- Collaborated with over 10 DuPage County, Illinois hospitals to provide inpatient hemodialysis treatments to hundreds of acutely and chronically ill patients with a wide variety of comorbidities.
- Led the administration of prescribed hemodialysis treatment by patient care staff to patients suffering from end stage renal disease.
- Analyzed and interpreted clinical data in regards to patient's treatment metrics, anemia, bone and mineral, and protein levels, and adjusted patient's clinical parameters to optimize treatment metrics and outcomes.
- Collaborated with the care coordination team, working closely with physicians, vascular surgeons, social workers, dietitians, and ancillary medical staff to coordinate and achieve optimal patient outcomes.
- Oversaw hemodialysis treatments in acute care settings such as intensive care units, cardiac telemetry units, medical-surgical units, oncology units, and psychiatric units.
- Managed hemodialysis registered nurses and technicians in initiation, duration, and termination of hemodialysis treatments.
- Monitored patients' response to hemodialysis treatments.
- Reviewed ordered medications by physicians for contraindications with patients' previous medical history.
- Arbitrated problems arising from treatment parameters both medical and psychosocial
- Performed objective patient assessment pre-treatment and post-treatment.
- Initiated and followed up with proper referrals in regards to access issues to physicians, vascular surgeons, social workers, dietitians, or other ancillary medical staff.

Lakewood Nursing and Rehabilitation Center/Courtyard Healthcare Center

- Supervised staff registered nurses, licensed practical nurses, and patient aide technicians in the care of patients in both acute and sub-acute rehabilitation units.
- Collaborated with an interdisciplinary team, which includes physicians, dietary/nutritional services, physical and occupational therapy, social services, case management, and MDS care plan coordinators, to bring about the best outcomes for patients.
- Provided and oversaw direct patient care, medication administrations, treatments, dressing changes, and monitoring of lab values to achieve the best standards of care as set by the offices of Medicare and Medicaid.
- Managed skilled nursing care for patients with complex multi-system disorders ranging from end stage renal disease, including patients on peritoneal dialysis and hemodialysis; cardiovascular disease, including patients with atrial fibrillation, uncontrolled hypertension, and congestive heart failure; cognitive and mental health disorders, including patients with schizophrenia, bipolar disorder, schizoaffective disorder, major depressive disorder; and other medical conditions, such as Parkinson's disease, Alzheimer's disease, and dementia.
- Analyzed clinical information in order to determine the best skilled nursing decisions in a
 variety of situations, while simultaneously and communicating with physicians regarding
 observed changes in patient status or condition, ongoing patient needs, abnormal lab values,
 necessary medications reconciliations or adjustments.
- Reconciled medication records against health history in order to identify and correct contraindications.
- Intervened in emergency situations such as rapid response and code blue scenarios as code leader to resuscitate patients in acute cardiac or respiratory failure.
- Educated staff, patients, and families on patient diagnosis, relevant clinical information, lab values, and medications.